Hyecheol (Jerry) Jang

□ (+1) 608-770-1154 | whyecheol.jang@wisc.edu | • hyecheol123 | • iphyecheol

Summary.

Interested in finding optimized solution using Cloud (MS Azure) and writing understandable codes. Passionate about new technolgies/languages/solutions. Experienced in backend/frontend development, deployment/operation, and project management. Open to full-time opportunities as a software developer or solution architect. Expect to graduate in May, 2023.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Madison, WI, United States

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE; DOUBLE MAJOR IN STATISTICS; MINOR IN ENTREPRENEURSHIP

Jul. 2018 - Current

- Dean's List: Fa18, Sp19, Sp20 | **GPA: 3.89/4.00**s
- Director of Technology at Korean American Scientist Association Wisconsin Chapter: Developed/Maintained NPO Chapter website and other useful IT tools for chapter management; responsible for various marketing, network activities, leadership board, and decision making.
- · Library Technology Student Assistant at College Library, Memorial Library, and CALS Computing Lab

Proiects_

KSEA-Wisconsin Event Ticket System

Madison, WI, United States

PROJECT MANAGER & BACK-END DEVELOPER

- Building automated event ticket generation / admission service for the NPO | Est. Release: Nov. 2022
- · Automatically send QR code with ticket information to the event participants, check ticket validity and todos during admission with officers' mobile device
- · Using Azure Function, Azure Blob Storage (for static website hosting), Azure Cosmos DB, CloudFlare (CDN) to minimize bandwidth, React Native

BusanDevelopers Event Calendar

Busan, South Korea

Jan 2022

PROJECT MANAGER & FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

- Successfully built web event calendar for devleopers community | Led project, Collaborated with one back-end developer and one front-end developer
- Used React (MUI), NodeJS, Azure Cosmos DB, ExpressJS, and ReDoc | Manually set TypeScript React environment using ESLint, Prettier, WebPack, and Babel
- · Effectively divided the project into smaller milestones, manage teammates' performance, and conduct weekly meetings

KSEA-Wisconsin Website Rebuilding Project

Madison, WI, United States

Nov. 2019

PROJECT MANAGER & DEVELOPER

- Built website for NPO Chapter | Led project, Collaborated with five developers | Used HTML, CSS, Jekyll, Git, Jira, MS Teams, Adobe XD
- · Divided tasks for collaboration accordingly | Provided training resources and counter errors and problems during the development process
- Successfully minimized operation budget GitHub Pages to host; used CloudFlare (CDN) to minimize bandwidth and yaml file database for easier modification
- V2 project now launched (Est. Release: Dec. 2022) Add admin portal (Web-based GUI), elegant design, Next.JS-powered website, Serve on MS Azure

CloudFlare Public Dynamic IP Update Script

Madison, WI, United States

Aug. 2019

• Built a script to update server's dynamic ip address to CloudFlare (DDNS) | Used Bash Shell Script | 50+ GitHub Star

Work Experience _

uniQon Seoul, South Korea

TECHNICAL LEAD

DEVELOPER

Apr. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Used NodeJS (TypeScript) and MongoDB to develop and operate API server, web page, and admin portal
- Elaborated idea and developed products that provide "real" college application data and mentor information to prospective applicants with their high school information, keywords from extracurricular activities, and target school lists and majors
- · Closely collaborated with CEO to build concrete business plans | Trained Interns/Software Developers and engage in HR tasks
- · Implemented IT infrastructure and remote working environment with Microsoft Teams, Jira, and GitHub
- · Adopt Agile software development workflow (Scrum) with weekly feedback to team/individuals | Traveled frequently for business meetings and recruiting

Republic of Korea Army

SOCIAL SERVICE AGENT (SOCIAL WELFARE)

Busan, South Korea

Oct. 2020 - Jul. 2022

· Served at Wonkwang Nursing Home (Long-Term Care Facilities) to complete mendatory military duty of South Korea

Honors & Awards _

AI·Blockchain Idea Pitching Competition (Third Edition)

Busan, South Korea

Presentation: Bird Strike Prevention Methods at Gadeokdo New Airport Using Big Data and Machine Learning

Skills

Programming Language: TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, SQL, R, C, Python, Bash

Cloud Service: Microsoft Azure AZ-900, AI-900, DP-900 Certified, Naver Cloud Platform, AWS, DigitalOcean (and VPS providers)

DB: Azure SQL, Azure Cosmos DB, mariaDB, mongoDB, redis

Misc: Linux/UNIX Server (Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS), Git, CloudFlare, React Redux, MUI (React Library), HTML, CSS, Arduino, Raspberry Pi

Language: English (Advanced), Korean (Native)

Aug. 2022